# Miguel Angel Ricaño

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

**SUMMARY** 

I'm a Full Stack Developer with great love to build apps to solve today's problems, who also dominate the arts of organization, negotiation, and mediation. Clean code and user experience are a must, fluent in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies, and capable of ramping up quickly and efficiently.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Microverse, Remote

Code Reviewer | March 2021 - Present

- I complete code reviews in HTML & CSS, Ruby, Rails, and Javascript for students.
- I propose Improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.

IK Sustainable, Xalapa, Mexico

eCommerce Manager | May 2020 - Present

- I Developed the website of the <u>brand</u> using liquid on Shopify.
- I maintain and implement new apps for the store.

The Rolland Collection, Bordeaux, France

Business Manager for LATAM and Asia | January 2012 - May 2014

- My staff was 3 salespeople, 2 marketers, and a financial administrator.
- I increased 30% in sales for Asia and 15% for Latin America.

Budhi, Mexico City, Mexico

Founder & Director | August 2010 - November 2011

- We developed Maat software, an administrative software build to emulate the decisions of professional admins applied to micro and small businesses that did not have access to administrative software.
- With a team of 4 developers and 3 administrative staff, Budhi was acquired by Grupo Carso in 2011.

## **EDUCATION**

Microverse | 2020 - 2021

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- I Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- I Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

EBS Paris - European Business School | 2012 –2014 Master of Business Administration, International Business Management (Incomplete)

Universidad Veracruzana | 2005 - 2010

Bachelor of Business Administration, International Business Management

www.miguelricano.me <u>Github</u> | <u>Linkedin</u> mricanho@gmail.com

## **SKILLS**

**Front-End**: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3

**Back-End**: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Liquid

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

**Professional**: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

## **PROJECTS**

# **EasyWeather**

- EasyWeather is a project to display the temp and weather's condition of the desired city in a cute way.
- Built with JavaScript, HTML5, Bulma.
- -Repository here.

#### **Sustyle**

- This is Sustyle, the website focused on the latest sustainability articles.
- Ruby on Rails, Ruby, Bulma, PostgreSQL.
- -Repository <u>here</u>.

### **VOLUNTEER**

Mentor, Microverse Mentored junior web developers

#### LANGUAGES

Spanish, Native English, C1 French, B1